<NATION id="wilbert">
<ISSUES>
<ISSUE id="1482">
<TITLE>A Crypto for the Comrades?</TITLE>
<TEXT>The recent craze of cryptocurrencies has taken Balder by storm, Wilbert chief among them. However, intense controversy has sprung up among the commissars regarding the impact these digital currencies have on the nation’s staunch socialist principles.</TEXT>
<AUTHOR>krusavich</AUTHOR>
<EDITOR>pogaria</EDITOR>
<PIC1>y22</PIC1>
<PIC2>y240</PIC2>
<OPTION id="0">“What are we to make of these internet coins?” sputters Stanislawa Gillard, your Minister of Computer Comradeship and Counter-Programming. “Totally detached from our central planning committee, no traceable records of transactions — nothing but a nuisance! The impressionable youth of Wilbert are trading these things for illicit goods, like capitalist skinny jeans and counter-revolutionary DVDs. Cryptocurrency is clearly nothing more than a destabilization tactic by the United Federation to undermine our mighty textbook! Our path is clear: we must detain and prosecute any citizen handling these subversive cryptocurrencies for the good of the Corporation!”</OPTION>
<OPTION id="1">“That, uh... seems a little extreme,” nervously suggests IT intern Barbara Mistletoe. “There’s actually a whole variety of cryptocurrencies; not all of them are anonymous like ByteCoin. The real benefit of crypto comes from the sheer versatility of transactions. I can exchange value with the push of a button! No middleman, no fees — just two comrades freely exchanging their labor with one another. And that is what this is all about, right? If we are so worried about the bad side of crypto, why not make our own? A completely transparent open-source cryptocurrency, maintained by the central government, of course. I’m sure no one here would complain about setting up another ministry to run the whole operation.”</OPTION>
<OPTION id="2">“Maybe those United Federation dogs have the right idea,” comments Internal Affairs Minister Fred Sullivan while using his phone to check his MemeCoin wallet. “The truth of the matter is that these coins demand a lot of computing power before you get anything valuable out of them. Most of these so-called miners only have mom’s laptop to work with — but we have the whole industrial might of Wilbert! Not to mention the personal computers of every Wilbertian, not that they need to know. A stockpile of these things would make our cadre funding in San Vitenzo harder to trace back to us, that’s for sure.”</OPTION>
</ISSUE>
<ISSUE id="1425">
<TITLE>The Corporate Wilbert’s New Clothes</TITLE>
<TEXT>In the midst of another busy day, you trip on a misplaced paperweight and tear your favorite pants on a nail haphazardly jutting out of your office’s door frame.</TEXT>
<AUTHOR>the_united_lands_of_ash</AUTHOR>
<EDITOR>the_free_joy_state</EDITOR>
<PIC1>p18</PIC1>
<PIC2>e15</PIC2>
<OPTION id="0">“Oh, this just won’t do!” tuts your aunt, an aspiring seamstress, holding two giant off-color swatches against your torn pants leg. “I’ll get this fixed right up, dearie! A few patches here and stitches there and they’ll be as good as new! Sad that so few people make-do-and-mend these days. Now, pass me your little pants.”</OPTION>
<OPTION id="1">Conan Gray, representative of the ancient tailors &lt;i&gt;The Leader’s Men&lt;/i&gt;, strolls into your office. “It is time for you to get new clothes anyway. Let us ditch these old rags and get you something more stylish. I see a classic yet breathable fabric that is sweat and bullet resistant, tailored to flatter your form and worn with ascots — not brogues.”</OPTION>
<OPTION id="3">Two brightly dressed men stumble into your office, with tailoring tape around their necks. “We’ve got just the thing for you, your mightiness! The greatest clothes in history, made just for your glorious self.” The first man flicks open a suitcase, revealing... nothing. “As you see, this fine cloth is lighter than air. Feel the fabric. It is too exquisite to waste on those buffoons at the Wilbertian Clothing Council. Surely, oh intelligent one, you can feel the delicate weave? These clothes are the future! People will praise your forward-thinking. Don’t worry about the price; we’ll just forward our small fee to your accountant.”</OPTION>
<OPTION id="4">“Malarkey! Why don’t you just dress like everyone else?” chimes your gardener through the window, watering the flowers on your desk along with everything and everyone in the room. “It’ll cost the taxpayer less, you’ll be more relatable, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; you won’t need to fuss about all that fancy-schmancy stuff! Heck, why not encourage all government officials to wear clothes that are affordable to the average Wilbertian!”</OPTION>
</ISSUE>
<ISSUE id="133">
<TITLE>When Zombie Wilberts Attack!</TITLE>
<TEXT>After several reports of pet Zombie Wilberts violently attacking, injuring, and even killing citizens, there has been growing pressure from public safety activists for the government to take action.</TEXT>
<AUTHOR>the_class_a_cows</AUTHOR>
<EDITOR>sirocco</EDITOR>
<PIC1>a2</PIC1>
<PIC2>a6</PIC2>
<OPTION id="0">“These creatures are a danger to the public and must be destroyed!” says Chun-Li Brewer, representative of the Public Institution for Social Safety, Equality, and Direction. “I was attacked by one just on the way here and I nearly lost my life! They’re a public menace. We must shoot and burn them!”</OPTION>
<OPTION id="1">“Why punish the poor things?” asks animal-lover Horatio Harrison, covered in scars from previous encounters with Zombie Wilberts. “All they need is good hands to care and rehabilitate them. We need a government education programme to tame them and turn them into loveable pets. The one I’m holding right now shows that it can be done. They are all good, kind creatures deep d- argh!”</OPTION>
<OPTION id="3">“Who cares!?” screams Megan Oliver, transmitting from a pirate radio station broadcast. “Just repeal any laws preventing us from gunning the things down when they attack and we’ll be able to save ourselves without this stupid, authoritarian, overbearing government and legal system wasting our tax money!”</OPTION>
</ISSUE>
<ISSUE id="336">
<TITLE>Polygamy Causes Division</TITLE>
<TEXT>The court system in Wilbert has ground to a halt since the record-breaking divorce case of serial-polygamist Matt Trimony, who has decided to divorce all 47 of his wives simultaneously. The case has become so lengthy and complex that lawyer-filled encampments have sprung up outside the building, preventing any new cases from being processed.</TEXT>
<AUTHOR>lordieth</AUTHOR>
<EDITOR>lenyo</EDITOR>
<PIC1>p4</PIC1>
<PIC2>p21</PIC2>
<OPTION id="0">“The courts just can’t cope with the strain,” warns Quentin Larkin, your trusted legal advisor. “Divorce cases have become so complex that lawyers now have to take courses in complex mathematics just to settle property disputes! If this continues any longer, our legal system is going to collapse. The best solution would be to make prenuptial agreements mandatory for all new marriages. That would free up the courts from dealing with complex property disputes once and for all.”</OPTION>
<OPTION id="1">“This is sacrilege!” exclaims Reverend Yasmin Sajak, bursting into your office without warning. “It was a mistake to legalize polygamy to begin with! It’s made a mockery of the sanctity of marriage. I implore the government to repeal this perversion of matrimony and make polygamy illegal throughout Wilbert - if not for the sake of the families it has torn apart, then for their very souls under the eyes of our great Lord.”</OPTION>
<OPTION id="2">“I’ve got a better idea,” claims renowned TV critic Barbie Amin, sprawling paperwork across your desk. “You want to keep polygamy legal, but don’t want to pay through the nose in legal fees, right? Why not broadcast the divorce proceedings live across Balder? Think of the drama! Think of the viewing figures! Just sign here on the dotted line, and the studio will cover all the expenses.” She forces a pen into your hand.</OPTION>
</ISSUE>
<ISSUE id="872">
<TITLE>Party On, The Corporate Wilbert!</TITLE>
<TEXT>Satirists have begun to take advantage of easygoing ballot access rules in Wilbert. This became particularly obvious when the &lt;i&gt;Society of Internationalist Liberal Localist Yuppies&lt;/i&gt; came within a hundred votes of winning a seat in parliament with a manifesto platform of “growing money on trees” and “popcorn for all”.</TEXT>
<AUTHOR>fauxia</AUTHOR>
<EDITOR>candlewhisper_archive</EDITOR>
<PIC1>x17</PIC1>
<PIC2>f6</PIC2>
<OPTION id="0">“How could we let this happen?” gasps the barely-victorious mainstream candidate, trying to ignore her opponent gamboling in the background with a 2-foot-tall foam mobile phone. “This so-called political party is a direct result of how loose our ballot access restrictions have become! We need to crack down on parties that don’t have realistic positions!”</OPTION>
<OPTION id="1">“Do we not have free speech?” questions Maxine Barrymore, the SILLY candidate, handing you an autographed copy of her book, &lt;i&gt;Jessica in Government&lt;/i&gt;. “My party receives votes as a protest against the status quo and against politicians who don’t listen. If the government and mainstream parties were to pay attention to voters for once, then maybe we wouldn’t need to exist! You must give us more direct democracy - referenda, public consultations and the right to have petitions discussed by parliament. Until then, we will defend our right to protest!”</OPTION>
<OPTION id="2">“You could learn a thing or two here!” exclaims comedian Jon Warden, handing you an aboriginal talking stick with ‘property of Lord Kettlenoggin’ written on it. “Spice up parliament by cracking a few jokes, dressing up in wacky ways, and capering a little. Don’t take politics or life so seriously - nothing is permanent.”</OPTION>
</ISSUE>

</ISSUES>
</NATION>

